sourcebottle.com.au 2017-11-26

# Free publicity for expert sources and PR professionals - connecting journalists, reporters, bloggers and writers with sources.

**The SourceBottle Pty Ltd (ACN 147 880 064)** (“ **we** ” or “ **us** ” or “ **our** ”) respects your privacy and we are committed to the protection of personal information.  We adhere to the Australian Privacy Principles as contained in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). The purpose of this Privacy Statement is to let you know how we collect, use and disclose your information.

#### Collection

“Personal information” refers to any information that is identifiable to you.  The Privacy Act also refers to “Sensitive information” which includes, but is not limited to, information about:

  * your health, fitness and nutrition
  * your personal beliefs and ideologies 
  * your goals with regard to medical or health treatment.

We only collect the information that is necessary to provide our services and to manage our activities.  The type of personal information we collect will depend upon the service that you wish to use.  Certain information is mandatory in order to use our service, as it is the foundation of our service in connecting Journalists, Writers and Bloggers with Sources.  If you do not wish to provide this information to us, then you will be unable to utilise our service. 

We do not solicit information from third parties.  Each person who registers with us should only provide information that relates to themselves, or the information of a third party if they have valid consent.

 **Sources**  
In order to register with us as a “Source” we require you to provide your full name and email address.  You will have the option of indicating the topics which you would like to be affiliated with as a Source.  If you would like to respond to a “Call Out” or “Request" you will need to provide your name and email address, and any further the information that you provide is up to you. 

**Expert Profile**  
In order to register as a Source with an “Expert Profile” we require you to provide your full name, and email address.  You have the option of providing your telephone number, qualifications and availability.  You may also choose to select key words to affiliate yourself with as an Expert, and you may choose to provide additional information about yourself.  The extent of the personal information that you provide voluntarily is within your own discretion. 

**Bloggers, Writers and Journalists**  
We require Journalists, Writers and Bloggers to provide us with your name, email address and the details of the Call Out that you would like us to publish. 

**Businesses and PR Professionals**  
If you subscribe to our “Find Giveaways” or “Find a Case Study” service we will require you to provide your name, email address and the details of the Request that you would like us to publish.

#### How we use your information

We will only use information for the purpose for which it is collected, to put Sources in touch with Journalists, Writers and Bloggers, and for Businesses and PR Professionals to make requests for giveaways, sponsorships and case studies.  We also use information for secondary purposes as you would reasonably expect, such as the management of our business. 

We communicate with our Sources by way of email in order to alert you to a call out or request that may interest you.  This is the way in which we provide our service, so while you can unsubscribe at any time, it will mean that you are no longer registered as a Source with us. 

We may at times use your email address in order to keep you updated with information about our services and where we do so, you will be able to opt out of receiving those emails at any time.

#### Disclosure

We do not provide any personal information to third parties other than where required by law or as set out in this Privacy Statement.

We may employ other companies or individuals to assist us in providing our services including to process payments.  We may also engage the services of third parties to assist us with our business providing marketing assistance or consulting services. These third parties may have access to information needed to perform their function but cannot use the information for another purpose.

 We will not sell, trade or rent your personal information to others. We may provide aggregate statistics on our customers and users of our website to third parties such as advertisers, but these statistics will not include personally identifying information.

We are an online business, and our website is available around the world.  Our website is hosted on a server situated in the United States of America.  We do not otherwise disclose personal information to any other country outside of Australia without your consent. 

**Sources**  
The only information that is disclosed automatically through our system is your email address and the name you have provided.  We do not disclose any other information.  If you wish to respond to a Call Out or Request, your submission will be converted into an email that is sent directly to the Journalist, Writer, Blogger, Business or PR Professional.

 **Bloggers, Journalists, Businesses and PR Professional**  
We do not disclose any information other than the details provided by you for the purposes of your Call Out or Request.

#### Keeping your Information

We only retain the information we require by law.  All of your information is held and handled securely by us. 

**Sources, Businesses and PR Professionals**  
Once you unsubscribe from our service, all of the information that you have provided to us will be deleted from our database and our systems.  We do not keep your information. 

**Journalists, Writers, Bloggers, Businesses and PR Professionals**  
Your information will only be held by us until the expiry date of your Call Out or Request, at which time it is deleted from our database and our systems.

#### Access, Correction and Complaints

It is important that your information is accurate at all times so we ask that you notify us of any changes that arise.  You should do this by logging on to your profile or subscription and updating your information.

You are entitled to request access to your information.  All queries or concerns should be put in writing to the attention of the Privacy Officer and emailed to: contact@sourcebottle.com. We will endeavour to respond to your concern within 30 days.

#### Cookies

As with most websites, we may use "cookies" to enhance User experience. Cookies do not cause damage or harm your system and are used to assist Users with our site.

#### Links

Our website may from time to time contain links to the websites of other organisations which may be of interest to you.  If you access linked sites, you do so at your own risk.  We do not operate or control these third party sites and we are not responsible for their contents, operation, privacy, accuracy or security policies.

 _We may from time to time make changes to this Privacy Statement.   The latest version of our Privacy Statement is available on our website.  We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect._
